<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
<title>TERMINALFOUR Sample Site Blog</title>
<link>https://samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/</link>
<description>T4 Sample Site Blog</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<generator>TERMINALFOUR</generator>
<copyright>Copyright: (C). TERMINALFOUR 2017</copyright><item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digital Disruption: Organizational Collaboration]]></title>  
            <link>https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/digital-disruption-organizational-collaboration-1.php</link> 
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/digital-disruption-organizational-collaboration-1.php</guid> 
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 15:36:00 GMT</pubDate> 
			<author>Claire Gibbons</author>
			<description><![CDATA[Digital Disruption: Organizational Collaboration. An overview.]]></description>
			<content:encoded>
            <![CDATA[
            <!doctype html>
            <html lang="en" prefix="op: http://media.facebook.com/op#">
              <head>
                <meta charset="utf-8">
                <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/digital-disruption-organizational-collaboration-1.php">
                <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">
              </head>
              <body>
                <article>
				  <header>
				    <figure><img src="http://samplesite.terminalfour.com/media/sample-site/site-assets/images/blog/banner-1.jpg" alt="" ></figure>
                  </header>
                  <h2>Digital Disruption: Organizational Collaboration</h2>
<p>Universities and large organizations are good at setting up projects – really good. At any one time, a Higher Education Institution will have projects covering all manner of activities – restructures, new IT systems, adoption of new legislation. They bring people together as a Team under the leadership of a Project Manager. They have budgets assigned to them. They have deliverables which may or may not be achieved. They create reports and ‘lessons learnt’. They are high profile and employees know about them.</p>
<p>And then they stop.</p>
<p>And so do the teams that were created, as well as the focus and attention that the project brought to that issue or opportunity. A project is finite – it has a beginning and an end – which is fine for completing one-off tasks in a timely and cost-effective way. However, digital transformation isn’t a one-off task to be completed. It is a journey, an evolution, a process, and as such, a different approach is required for it to be a success.</p>
<p>That approach is collaboration. Collaboration isn’t a one-off – it’s a culture, a way of working, and needs to be continuous and permeate across the institution continually.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>“The age of the collaboration, of the team, of the group, is emerging”,&nbsp;</em>Gerry McGovern</p>
</blockquote>
                </article>
              </body>
            </html>
            ]]>
          </content:encoded>
      </item><item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digital Disruption: Organizational Collaboration]]></title>  
            <link>https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/digital-disruption-organizational-collaboration.php</link> 
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/digital-disruption-organizational-collaboration.php</guid> 
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 15:36:00 GMT</pubDate> 
			<author>Claire Gibbons</author>
			<description><![CDATA[Digital Disruption: Organizational Collaboration. An overview.]]></description>
			<content:encoded>
            <![CDATA[
            <!doctype html>
            <html lang="en" prefix="op: http://media.facebook.com/op#">
              <head>
                <meta charset="utf-8">
                <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/digital-disruption-organizational-collaboration.php">
                <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">
              </head>
              <body>
                <article>
				  <header>
				    <figure><img src="http://samplesite.terminalfour.com/media/sample-site/site-assets/images/blog/banner-1.jpg" alt="" ></figure>
                  </header>
                  <h2>Digital Disruption: Organizational Collaboration</h2>
<p>Universities and large organizations are good at setting up projects – really good. At any one time, a Higher Education Institution will have projects covering all manner of activities – restructures, new IT systems, adoption of new legislation. They bring people together as a Team under the leadership of a Project Manager. They have budgets assigned to them. They have deliverables which may or may not be achieved. They create reports and ‘lessons learnt’. They are high profile and employees know about them.</p>
<p>And then they stop.</p>
<p>And so do the teams that were created, as well as the focus and attention that the project brought to that issue or opportunity. A project is finite – it has a beginning and an end – which is fine for completing one-off tasks in a timely and cost-effective way. However, digital transformation isn’t a one-off task to be completed. It is a journey, an evolution, a process, and as such, a different approach is required for it to be a success.</p>
<p>That approach is collaboration. Collaboration isn’t a one-off – it’s a culture, a way of working, and needs to be continuous and permeate across the institution continually.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>“The age of the collaboration, of the team, of the group, is emerging”,&nbsp;</em>Gerry McGovern</p>
</blockquote>
                </article>
              </body>
            </html>
            ]]>
          </content:encoded>
      </item><item>
            <title><![CDATA[What I took away from this year&rsquo;s Noel-Levitz conference]]></title>  
            <link>https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/what-i-took-away-from-this-years-noel-levitz-conference.php</link> 
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/what-i-took-away-from-this-years-noel-levitz-conference.php</guid> 
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 15:40:15 GMT</pubDate> 
			<author>S&eacute;an Walsh</author>
			<description><![CDATA[What I took away from this year’s Noel-Levitz conference]]></description>
			<content:encoded>
            <![CDATA[
            <!doctype html>
            <html lang="en" prefix="op: http://media.facebook.com/op#">
              <head>
                <meta charset="utf-8">
                <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/what-i-took-away-from-this-years-noel-levitz-conference.php">
                <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">
              </head>
              <body>
                <article>
				  <header>
				    <figure><img src="http://samplesite.terminalfour.com/media/sample-site/site-assets/images/blog/banner-2.jpg" alt="" ></figure>
                  </header>
                  <h2>Measure, measure and measure</h2>
<p>‘Do you know if your marketing is performing’? Marketing often struggles to prove its value. People know it helps and they know they need to ‘do it’ but because it is perceived as a spending function it has sometimes been unable to prove its direct impact on organizational goals. This is why marketers love digital marketing. You can measure visits, conversions, hits, downloads, requests and a million other factors. It’s the reason why every marketing person has bought the t-shirt saying ‘If you can’t measure it you can’t manage it’ or the latest iteration’ if you can’t measure it you can’t improve it’.</p>
<p><br>Measuring is vital. You should be able to track to conversion, you should have tracking codes on every web page, you should be A/B testing, you should be measuring and analyzing key word impact. The overwhelming message from the conference was measure, measure, measure. But a word to the wise; just because you can’t measure something doesn’t mean it doesn’t have an impact. This relates back to the offline debate. You don’t know the impact of a person seeing your billboard driving through your city when they were on vacation with their parents last year. You don’t know that that billboard encouraged them to go to your website when they got home and request more information. You can’t throw the baby out with the bathwater because offline is difficult to track and measure; its impact just may be very real.</p>
<h2>Be part of the conversation</h2>
<p>‘Why do we not connect storytelling to strategy’? One of the big themes of the conference was engagement; connecting your audiences and have meaningful conversations with them. Universities and colleges need to communicate with purpose and intent. They need to be conscious of the organizational goals but understand how storytelling, in all its forms, can deliver on them. A simple example is around student recruitment. Are you just disseminating information about the university or a specific course? Or are you, for example, letting a current student or recent graduate tell their story (perhaps through video)about how they’ve achieved something significant to them by attending your university or graduating with ‘that degree’. This is powerful, impactful and memorable. ‘A picture is worth a thousand words. One minute of video is worth 1.8 million words’</p>
<h2>The Keynote: From Homeless to Harvard</h2>
<p>It’s very rare that a key note at a conference can render an entire conference room of 1,500+ plus silent for an hour but that’s exactly what happened when Liz Murray took to the stage. If you didn’t know her story to be true you’d never believe it could be. From living with drug addicted parents, through abject poverty, through her parents’ death and homelessness to becoming a Harvard graduate, her self-told story (without self-pity or judgement) was inspirational and transformational. Her belief in ‘What if…?’ will change the way you think about your own life and situation. ‘What if’ the 150th door you open (after 149th slap you in the face) is the one that changes your life. Hers is a story of how education gave her a future and helped her be at peace with her past. It’s too hard to convey her message in a short blog but I bought her book, ‘Breaking Night: A memoir of forgiveness, survival and my journey from homeless to Harvard’- I’d recommend you do too.</p>
                </article>
              </body>
            </html>
            ]]>
          </content:encoded>
      </item><item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 creative websites from art &amp; design schools]]></title>  
            <link>https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/5-creative-websites-from-art--design-schools.php</link> 
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/5-creative-websites-from-art--design-schools.php</guid> 
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 15:36:00 GMT</pubDate> 
			<author>Dave O'Dwyer</author>
			<description><![CDATA[5 of the best website designs from design universities and colleges]]></description>
			<content:encoded>
            <![CDATA[
            <!doctype html>
            <html lang="en" prefix="op: http://media.facebook.com/op#">
              <head>
                <meta charset="utf-8">
                <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/5-creative-websites-from-art--design-schools.php">
                <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">
              </head>
              <body>
                <article>
				  <header>
				    <figure><img src="http://samplesite.terminalfour.com/media/sample-site/site-assets/images/blog/banner-1.jpg" alt="" ></figure>
                  </header>
                  <p>The university website is an unparalleled resource not only when it comes to informing students about what your institution has to offer but it also goes a long way towards establishing the identity of your university or college.</p>
<p>The above statement is never truer than when it comes to art and design school websites. &nbsp;You know that uncomfortable sense of foreboding and ominous dread you get when the person cutting your hair is sporting a particularly unflattering or crazy new hairstyle? Well it’s kind of the same principle for art-schools; you just expect more from the design of their websites. Just like you expect your hairdresser to have good hair, you expect a school devoted to design to feature a good web design.</p>
<p>The website is at the very core of a university or college’s website and an art or design school has more to prove in terms of its artistic abilities. We have recently spent some time looking at some of the websites offerings from art and design institutions and have picked what we think are five of the best around. We weren’t just looking for eye-catching designs, we also didn’t want to compromise on user experience. All five of the websites feature stunning designs and are easy to navigate.&nbsp;</p>
                </article>
              </body>
            </html>
            ]]>
          </content:encoded>
      </item><item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 20 most searched universities in the world on Google]]></title>  
            <link>https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/the-20-most-searched-universities-in-the-world-on-google.php</link> 
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/the-20-most-searched-universities-in-the-world-on-google.php</guid> 
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 15:41:46 GMT</pubDate> 
			<author>Louise Ryan</author>
			<description><![CDATA[How SEO can help increase your online popularity]]></description>
			<content:encoded>
            <![CDATA[
            <!doctype html>
            <html lang="en" prefix="op: http://media.facebook.com/op#">
              <head>
                <meta charset="utf-8">
                <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/the-20-most-searched-universities-in-the-world-on-google.php">
                <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">
              </head>
              <body>
                <article>
				  <header>
				    <figure><img src="http://samplesite.terminalfour.com/media/sample-site/site-assets/images/blog/banner-3.jpg" alt="" ></figure>
                  </header>
                  <p>We found the recent results concerning the<a title="google" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-29240959" target="_blank">&nbsp;20 most searched universities in the world on Google</a>&nbsp;to be most surprising and therefore decided that a blog post was in order.</p>
<p>The results were provided by the search engine Google at the request of the BBC and are quite different to other league tables as they show that the most prestigious and highest ranking universities aren’t the most searched for institutions.</p>
<p>Before seeing the results, we were prepared to see names like Caltech, MIT, Harvard, Oxford and Princeton dominating the top spots but it’s just not the case.</p>
<p>While heavy weights like Harvard, Stanford and Oxford do feature in the top 20 they’re nowhere near as googled as you might think.</p>
<p>So what is the most googled university then? It may surprise you to know that the accolade goes to Arizona’s own University of Phoenix with MIT and the Open University finishing in second and third place consecutively.</p>
<p>What’s especially interesting about this list is that it feeds neatly into what’s been happening in higher education over the past number of years. Once upon a time, prestige and reputation were the bread and butter of an institution; however there are more factors to consider these days and an online reputation is becoming far more influential. Students are no longer waiting to be fed information, they’re actively leaving no stone unturned; trawling the internet for the school that’s best tailored to their unique, individual needs. A university with a web presence that’s lacking or noticeably absent just can’t compete with an institution that’s got an impressively visible web presence.</p>
<p>If you’re wondering how to improve your university’s online reputation then there are a few golden rules you need to follow:</p>
<h3>Invest in SEO</h3>
<p>Even small investments in SEO can make a noticeable improvement in how your university ranks in Google searches. A comprehensive SEO strategy is certainly worth investing in to find out what searches your university (and your competitors) is performing well in and what areas you are underperforming in. Play to your strengths and you should reap the rewards.</p>
<h3>Write great content...often</h3>
<p>We know we’re always droning on about how &nbsp;content is king of the online castle but if you want to increase your university’s visibility online and get yourself onto Google’s radar then you need to be writing great content on a regular basis. We’re not talking holidays and special occasions here, we mean on a weekly and even daily basis. Blogging actively (and well) is one of the best ways to help you achieve this. If users &nbsp;like what you have to say then pretty soon they’ll be googling you just as often as you are uploading blog posts.</p>
<h3>Use Alt tags</h3>
<p>The basic rule of search engine optimization is to provide content that satisfies the purpose of your users visit. When writing content you should always be asking; “What information does the user need to know?” Make sure you answer these questions in the fastest and most direct way possible. Usability is extremely important so ensure that you use descriptive and concise Alt tags for any images. If Google doesn’t know what it’s looking at then this will affect your ranking.</p>
<p>There’s no magic overnight solution that will increase your ranking online but over time and with a solid investment in your online strategy you should begin to see an increase in web traffic and in turn an increase in web conversions.&nbsp;</p>
                </article>
              </body>
            </html>
            ]]>
          </content:encoded>
      </item><item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to harness the power of the international student blog]]></title>  
            <link>https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/how-to-harness-the-power-of-the-international-student-blog.php</link> 
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/how-to-harness-the-power-of-the-international-student-blog.php</guid> 
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 15:40:00 GMT</pubDate> 
			<author>Louise Ryan</author>
			<description><![CDATA[3 great examples of international student blogs]]></description>
			<content:encoded>
            <![CDATA[
            <!doctype html>
            <html lang="en" prefix="op: http://media.facebook.com/op#">
              <head>
                <meta charset="utf-8">
                <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.samplesite.terminalfour.com/life-at-t4u/blog/blog-posts/how-to-harness-the-power-of-the-international-student-blog.php">
                <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">
              </head>
              <body>
                <article>
				  <header>
				    <figure><img src="http://samplesite.terminalfour.com/media/sample-site/site-assets/images/blog/banner-6.jpg" alt="" ></figure>
                  </header>
                  <p>Blogs are now one of the most influential digital resources available to consumers when making a purchasing decision. They have become an integral part of how we research products and services and how we make consumer decisions from what book to read next, where to go on holidays to what brand of laptop to buy.</p>
<p>Blogging has become an extra step in the consumer thought process and a favorable or indeed a less than favorable review can turn a previously steadfast opinion entirely on its head.</p>
<p>So, why exactly are blogs so influential?</p>
<p>The answer’s a simple one: Bloggers tend to be pretty honest in how they review products and services. They talk about what aspects of a certain product they like but they also don’t shy away from what aspects they don’t like. Trust is after all what drives consumers to act.</p>
<p>Blogging is an especially important step when consumers are dealing with a brand that is unfamiliar to them. The same is true when it comes to students who are researching what university or college to attend abroad. While domestic students may recognize your brand, international students are less likely to be familiar with what exactly it is that sets you apart from your competitors.</p>
<p>We’ve recently written a blog post about why&nbsp;<a href="http://www.terminalfour.com/blog/posts/why-mastering-the-art-of-the-student-blog-is-a-must-for-any-university-.html">mastering the art of student blogging is a must for any university</a>&nbsp;and today we want to focus more on international student blogging and why it’s vital for any institution who hopes to attract foreign students.</p>
<p>Universities and college that have an active blog written by and for international students stand a far better chance of appealing to an international student audience. A blog that is written by an international student about their honest experiences of attending your university can be a powerful way of marketing your international studies programme. They can provide insight into cultural differences, tourist attractions, what the support system is like for international students, how to find accommodation and what classes to take.</p>
<p>We actually found it quite challenging to find examples of universities and colleges who are consistently updating their international student blog. However, after trawling the internet we have found 3 universities who we think are doing a pretty great job running their international student blogs:</p>
<ol>
<li>&nbsp;<a href="http://asiapacific.anu.edu.au/news-events/all-stories/yia-blog-all" target="_blank">ANU College of Asia and the Pacific</a></li>
<li><a title="UCC" href="https://uccinternational.wordpress.com/">University College Cork</a>&nbsp;</li>
<li><a href="http://www.aston.ac.uk/international-students/why-choose-aston/meet-aston-international-scholars/" target="_blank">Aston University</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Prove us wrong! Does your university or college have an active international student blog that you would like to share with us? Leave a comment below or email us at marketing [at] terminalfour.com</p>
                </article>
              </body>
            </html>
            ]]>
          </content:encoded>
      </item>
</channel>
</rss>